export const GEOGRAPHYA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. What is the scale of the map?",
A: "1:50,000",
B: "1:100,000",
C: "1:150,000",
D: "1:200,000",
answer: "B. 1:100,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The highest contour line on the map is",
A: "800 m.",
B: "750 m.",
C: "730 m.",
D: "700 m.",
answer: "A. 800 m",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which area of the map can the trigonometrical station be found?",
A: "North east",
B: "Southeast",
C: "North west",
D: "Southwest",
answer: "C. North west",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. What is the approximate length of the railway line on the map?",
A: "29 km.",
B: "37 km",
C: "40 km",
D: "45 km",
answer: "B. 37 km",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. R. Kafue takes its source from a",
A: "plateau.",
B: "ridge.",
C: "knoll.",
D: "conical hill.",
answer: "B. ridge",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The feature marked P is a",
A: "mountain.",
B: "spur.",
C: "knoll.",
D: "valley.",
answer: "B. spur",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The northern part of the map is suitable for",
A: "mining.",
B: "trading.",
C: "lumbering.",
D: "farming.",
answer: "D. farming",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. What type of settlement is ALADE?",
A: "Nodal",
B: "Coastal",
C: "Dry valley",
D: "Linear",
answer: "A. Nodal",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. What is the bearing of the trigonometrical station from Ilo on the map?",
A: "168°",
B: "178°",
C: "190°",
D: "200°",
answer: "C. 190°",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The most important settlement in the area is",
A: "Ilo.",
B: "Ilapo.",
C: "Aso.",
D: "ALADE.",
answer: "D. ALADE",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The annual range of temperature for the station is",
A: "1°C.",
B: "2°C.",
C: "22°C.",
D: "28°C.",
answer: "B. 2°C",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. From which climatic region were the figures taken?",
A: "Desert",
B: "Mediterranean",
C: "Equatorial",
D: "Tropical Monsoon",
answer: "C. Equatorial",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following towns experiences the type of climate represented in the table?",
A: "Gao (Mali)",
B: "Cairo (Egypt)",
C: "Warri (Nigeria)",
D: "London (England)",
answer: "C. Warri (Nigeria)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. What is the mean temperature from July to December?",
A: "16.5°C",
B: "17.2°C",
C: "27.5°C",
D: "28.0°C",
answer: "C. 27.5°C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In Koppen’s classification of climates, C’s refers to",
A: "Steppe.",
B: "Mediterranean.",
C: "Tropical Monsoon.",
D: "Tropical Continental.",
answer: "B. Mediterranean",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following features is associated with river capture?",
A: "Delta",
B: "Meander",
C: "Levee",
D: "Wind gap",
answer: "D. Wind gap",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Volcanoes that have erupted before and show signs of possible eruption again are said to be",
A: "weak.",
B: "extinct.",
C: "dormant.",
D: "on-going.",
answer: "C. dormant",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. In the northern hemisphere, summer solstice is experienced on",
A: "September 22.",
B: "June 21.",
C: "December 22.",
D: "March 21.",
answer: "B. June 21",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A community of plants and animals living in harmony within the same physical environment is referred to as",
A: "environmental interaction.",
B: "terrestrial bio-cycle.",
C: "ecosystem.",
D: "biosphere.",
answer: "C. ecosystem",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Sea breeze is most effective at",
A: "winter.",
B: "daytime.",
C: "summer.",
D: "nighttime",
answer: "B. daytime",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The nearest planet to the sun is",
A: "Jupiter.",
B: "Saturn.",
C: "Mercury.",
D: "Earth.",
answer: "C. Mercury",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The type of rainfall mostly experienced within the tropics is",
A: "fog.",
B: "relief.",
C: "frontal.",
D: "convectional.",
answer: "D. convectional",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A feature commonly found in the youthful stage of a river is",
A: "levee.",
B: "meander.",
C: "ox-bow lake.",
D: "interlocking spur.",
answer: "D. interlocking spur",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is not a characteristic of Wadis?",
A: "They are river channels",
B: "They occur in tropical areas",
C: "They hold permanent streams",
D: "They have steep craggy walls",
answer: "C. They hold permanent streams",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Stalactites and Stalagmites are associated with which type of the following rocks?",
A: "Granite",
B: "Sandstone",
C: "limestone",
D: "Basalt",
answer: "C. limestone",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. What is the time in Accra (longitude 0°) when the local time at (longitude 45° W) is 12 noon?",
A: "3.00 pm",
B: "5.00 pm",
C: "7.00 pm",
D: "9.00 pm",
answer: "A. 3.00 pm",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. What is the distance between two places on the surface of the earth which are located 8°N and 10° S on the same longitude?",
A: "1,011km",
B: "1,998 km",
C: "10,101km",
D: "17,770 km",
answer: "B. 1,998 km",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Coastal deposition results in the formation of",
A: "sack.",
B: "arch.",
C: "pillar.",
D: "beach.",
answer: "D. beach",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following pairs of elements are found in the core of the earth?",
A: "Iron and Silicon",
B: "Iron and Nickel",
C: "Iron and Calcium",
D: "Iron and Magnesium",
answer: "B. Iron and Nickel",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. In which of the following layers in the atmosphere does temperature increases with altitude?",
A: "Troposphere",
B: "Ionosphere",
C: "Stratosphere",
D: "Exosphere",
answer: "C. Stratosphere",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Relief rainfall is mostly associated with",
A: "lowlands.",
B: "peneplains.",
C: "highlands.",
D: "deserts.",
answer: "C. highlands",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The extent of coastal erosion depends on the",
A: "amount of fresh water supplied by tributaries.",
B: "depth of ocean water.",
C: "salinity of the ocean.",
D: "nature of waves.",
answer: "D. nature of waves",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The envelope of gases surrounding the earth’s crust is called",
A: "hydrosphere.",
B: "barysphere.",
C: "atmosphere.",
D: "lithosphere.",
answer: "C. atmosphere",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Carbonaceous type of sedimentary rocks are made from",
A: "remains of dead animals.",
B: "vegetative matter.",
C: "molten magma.",
D: "living plants and animals.",
answer: "B. vegetative matter",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Autotrophs, heterotrophs and decomposers are associated with",
A: "vegetation.",
B: "Climates",
C: "Ecosystem.",
D: "Geology.",
answer: "C. Ecosystem",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following pairs of rocks is not correctly shown?",
A: "clay → slate",
B: "limestone → marble",
C: "sandstone → quartzite",
D: "shale → graphite",
answer: "D. shale → graphite",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Cold currents can also cause",
A: "rise in tide.",
B: "rise in temperature of an area.",
C: "sea level to rise",
D: "fogs instead of actual rain.",
answer: "D. fogs instead of actual rain",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The most predominant occupation of most of the population of West African countries is",
A: "farming.",
B: "fishing.",
C: "mining.",
D: "teaching.",
answer: "A. farming",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following is not a characteristic of subsistence farming?",
A: "The produce is mainly for home consumption",
B: "It is capital intensive",
C: "Simple farming tools are used",
D: "It is labour intensive",
answer: "B. It is capital intensive",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Trans-continental highways link up",
A: "mining cities.",
B: "countries in a continent.",
C: "state headquarters.",
D: "local settlements.",
answer: "B. countries in a continent",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Heavy industries require",
A: "mostly coal to run them.",
B: "cheap raw materials as inputs.",
C: "generators only as source of electricity.",
D: "large capital to set up.",
answer: "D. large capital to set up",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following is likely to make petroleum drilling unimportant?",
A: "Depletion of reserves",
B: "Adequate capital",
C: "Adequate skilled labour",
D: "Good management",
answer: "A. Depletion of reserves",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following statements mostly apply to solar energy production in Tropical Africa?",
A: "Generates without cost",
B: "Imported from Europe",
C: "Produced in higher latitudes",
D: "Readily accessible and cheap",
answer: "D. Readily accessible and cheap",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. They are headquarters of government and are usually capital cities. This statement best describes",
A: "market towns.",
B: "administrative towns.",
C: "educational towns.",
D: "mining towns.",
answer: "B. administrative towns",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. One of the usefulness of tariff on imported goods is the",
A: "encouragement of importations.",
B: "multiplication of foreign goods.",
C: "protection of infant industries.",
D: "saving of money.",
answer: "C. protection of infant industries",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The location of textile industries are commonly",
A: "near the market.",
B: "where water resource is scarce.",
C: "in wide plains.",
D: "near sources of raw materials.",
answer: "D. near sources of raw materials",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following factors is unique for the development of the aircraft industry in California?",
A: "Availability of cheap labour",
B: "The peaceful political atmosphere",
C: "The government limited support",
D: "Clear sky which favours testing of aircrafts",
answer: "D. Clear sky which favours testing of aircrafts",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The ranking of settlements into rural and urban is mostly based on",
A: "location.",
B: "size.",
C: "pattern.",
D: "population.",
answer: "D. population",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. All the following agricultural practices are intensive farming techniques except",
A: "land rotation",
B: "crop rotation",
C: "mixed farming.",
D: "market gardening.",
answer: "A. land rotation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Natural increase in population means excess of",
A: "emigration over immigration.",
B: "immigration over emigration.",
C: "deaths over births.",
D: "births over deaths.",
answer: "D. births over deaths",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]